ReEncoded By Dr.XJ | PSA
www.PSArips.com
Tomorrow we will bury this one.
This Pipe Person.
Our messenger to Wah-kon-tah.
It is time to bury this Pipe
with dignity...
...and put away its teachings.
The children outside listening...
...they will learn another language.
They will be taught by white people.
They will learn new ways...
...and will not know our ways.
Phillips Oil workmen,
right here.
Kraceon Oil
pipeline crew, over here.
Burbank Oil Field, over here.
Marland Oil!
Rock hounds
for Phillips Oil, this truck.
Make it rich. You can make it
rich. Make it rich. Right here.
Phillips Oil workmen!
Ernest!
Yeah.
- Ernest Burkhart?
- Henry. - Yeah.
Henry Roan.
- I'm taking you to your uncle Hale.
- All right.
Come on. Let's go.
This is us, right here.
Come on, stop!
Whose land is this, Henry?
My land.
Well, well, well.
Our war hero has arrived.
Welcome home, Ernest.
Welcome home.
It's so good to see you again.
I'm so glad you made it.
Brother.
- Thanks for writin', huh?
- Good to have you back, Brother.
Ernest, now, here's your aunt
Myrtle and your cousin, little Willie.
Welcome. It's so good
to see you.
Look how big she's grown.
Isn't that something?
Now, this is a cattle ranch.
There's no oil here.
No oil? Yeah. No oil, no fear,
so I'm settled with no fear.
Time will run out.
This wealth will run dry,
drier than the seven years of famine
that plagued the pharaohs of old.
They're a sick people.
They're kindly people, big-hearted
people, but they're sickly.
What about you?
You see bloodshed?
- Some.
- Mm-hmm.
Well, I was a... I was a
cook in... in the infantry.
You see Kelsie Morrison?
He was over there.
- I did.
- Yeah.
Otis Griggs and the others,
if... if you remember.
Soldiers have to eat. You fed
the soldiers that won the war.
- Well, saw more die from the flu, but...
- Mmm.
So what happened
to your stomach?
My... My gut, it burst.
You almost lost your life.
They gave me a belt and told me
not to do any heavy lifting.
Well, you made a good choice
coming back here, 'cause here...
I know.
Money flows freely here, now.
Well, I do...
I do love that money, sir.
Don't call me "sir."
You call me "Uncle,"
or call me "King," like
you used to. Remember?
- Call you "King"?
- Yeah.
King.
Now, you didn't pick up
any disease over there, did you?
- No. No.
- Sure?
I'm sure, sir. I'm sure.
Not that I know of.
You keep that thing
wrapped up over there?
- I did. I did.
- Mmm.
- As best you could.
- As best I could.
Yeah.
You like women?
Ah, you know I like women.
That's my weakness.
What kinds they got out there?
- Just white.
- Just white, that I saw. - Hmm.
You like red?
Red?
- You mean - that kind of red?
- Mm-hmm.
I like red. I like white.
I like blue.
I like all of 'em.
- Don't matter to me. I'm greedy.
- Mmm.
I... I like the heavy ones. I like
the heavy ones, pretty ones, soft,
ones that smell good, you know.
Well, we gotta keep an eye
on you. You're all over the place.
Uh, speaking of that...
Hey, Byron.
Yeah.
Oh, yeah, that's good.
That's... That's real good.
Don't get played out in the open
with alcohol, you hear?
'Cause then
you'll cause trouble.
- Right, Byron?
- That's right, King.
- Mmm.
- No, sir. I w... I won't. I won't.
Now, most fellas out here
are crooked.
Some do things right, most
do bad, so don't be simple.
- No, sir. I won't.
- Don't make small trouble about nothing.
You gonna make trouble,
make it big.
Get a big payoff for that,
you hear?
Yes, sir.
You see, I am officially
reserve deputy sheriff in Fairfax.
I don't want to bring
unwanted eyes.
- I won't find that trouble.
- Yeah.
I won't do stupid things.
And you got your head on
straight after being over there?
Course I do. I'm not... I'm not
thick, sir. I'm... I'm... I'm strong.
Well, I got a place
I'm gonna put you.
- That'll be driving.
- Mmm.
'Cause you can't do much else
'cause of your gut.
You don't read much, do you?
Read?
Do you read, yeah. Read much?
Well, I can read.
Eh. Well,
you smarten yourself up.
Get him that book
on the Osage, Byron.
- This one?
- Yeah, that one.
- You smarten yourself up.
- I... I can read, sir.
The Osage.
They have the worst land possible...
...but the good Lord,
he outsmarted everybody.
The land had oil on it.
Black gold.
But they're wise people.
They worked it so as they had the say
who gets the oil, who gets the headrights.
The Osage are sharp.
They don't talk much,
so that might make you feel
like you've got to run
your mouth to fill the space,
especially you been drinking.
Better you be quiet if you
don't got nothing smart to say.
Don't get caught on that.
It's what they call,
"blackbird talk."
Blackbird talk.
Just 'cause they're not talking,
don't mean they don't know
everything about everything.
Yeah, Osage are the finest and
most beautiful people on God's earth.
John Whitehair, age 23.
No investigation.
Bill Stepson, age 29.
Anna Sanford, age 41.
No investigation.
Rose Lewis...
age 25.
No investigation.
There we go.
And Sara Butler, age 21.
Suicide.
State your name.
I'm Mollie Kyle. Incompetent.
What is your allotment number?
Two hundred eighty-five.
You've asked for
additional moneys of $752
to pay a medical bill
for an abscess.
Yes, sir.
Was the operation successful?
And the diabetes?
I have a prescription at Fairfax Drugs.
I'll send my help to fill twice monthly.
You gotta look out for that,
you know.
Now, Mollie, it's your mother.
You know she's restricted too, so
we have to account for every penny.
It says here she spent
$319 and 05 cents for meat
at the grocery.
Don't you think that's an awful
lot of meat for what she needs?
Yes, Mr. Beaty.
Well, you'll look after that,
won't you?
Yes.
All right, people. Let's form a
line here for allotment payments.
Unrestricted only.
Restricted, take your guardian. He
has to be with you to sign your checks.
You need to find your guardian.
Nothing new this time, folks.
Thirty-dollar photo
for posterity.
Don't you wanna preserve
your family history? Come on.
How about you, sir? You... Now,
don't go after him.
He don't know nothing.
He's an amateur.
You need a proper photo
for you and your family.
For you, sir? $40.
How much? $40?$40.
All right. I got $35
cash for you right now.
- Take it or leave it.
- Thirty-five's a deal.
Let's have it, get it done.
Y'all are gonna make
a pretty picture.
Y'all, come on this way,
over here.
My wife's been feeling poorly.
The doctor says it's her constitution.
The boy's got asthma.
His asthma's holding him back.
He just needs a chance.
You've got your checks.
You're unrestricted. Please.
We'll take one. In that color.
- Thank you.
- Thank you!
I'll tell you what, you run
out of gas, you get a flat tire,
you come right on back
and buy another.
Ma'am, you need a ride?
That's my bucket, right there.
Thank you.
Gotta be careful. A lot of
characters around here today.
Hey, Ernest!
Hey, Kelsie Morrison!
- We were at the front - together in France.
- Hey!
- How you doing? - Great to see you!
- You too. You too.
My wife, Catherine Cole.
Oh, pleased to meet you.
Pleased to meet you.
Full blood.
Sky People, right? Sky People?
Middle Water. Middle Water.
Lot of money on this.
Whoo!
You got money on this race?
No. No.
Let's go, then.
Yep.
I'm sorry to hear
she's not doing good.
You know, Father,
just as stubborn as ever.
Tell your mom I'm praying
for her, okay?
- Take care. Yeah.
- Thank you, Father.
You know who I mean
when I say Mollie Kyle?
You know the one,
with the sisters.
- I know which one.
- Mollie. - Yeah. Mollie.
She lives with her mother, Lizzie.
I know, Uncle, which one.
I know her.
I've bee...
I've been driving her.
- Driving her?
- Yeah.
Matt Williams used
to go with her for a time.
They're not together
in a way now,
so that means
you could have a proposition
with that if that struck you.
You want... You want me
to see after her.
- She's a regular customer of mine.
- Yeah.
I think she...
She's sweet on me too.
- That Mollie, - she's easy to like. Yeah.
- Yeah.
Full blood estate, at that, too.
- Full... Full blood estate.
Now, that's something
a man can work with, hmm?
You got a good face,
you know that?
Think you can be
the marrying kind?
- Marrying kind?
- Mm-hmm.
Uh, how do you mean?
Well, we mix
these families together,
and that estate money flows
the right direction, it'll come to us.
That's a full blood estate. And she
gets that money of the mother Lizzie.
Now, that's good business there.
And legal, not against the law.
That's smart investment.
They told me you was... you was
going with Matt Williams for a time.
You talk too much.
Nah. Nah, I don't talk too much.
Just thinking who I gotta beat
in this horse race, that's all.
I didn't realize
this was a race.
I don't care
for watching horses.
Well, I'm a different
kind of horse.
What?
What was that?
That's how you are.
I don't know what you said, but it
must've been Indian for "handsome devil."
All right.
"I am an Osage brave."
A long time ago,
"we Osage took our name
from Missouri and Osage Rivers."
"Ni-U-Kon-Ska,
Children of the Middle Waters."
'Move, ' said
the Great White Father,
from Missouri, from Arkansas,
from Kansas.
Finally, another strange land,
Oklahoma,
where famine walked by day
and hungry wolves by night.
"Can you find the wolves
in this picture?"
All right, let's go. Come on.
"Osage weren't ever part
of the Five Civilized Tribes."
- You remember Blackie Thompson?
- Howdy, boys!
"Of the Five Civilized Tribes,
the Cherokee, Chickasaw,
Choctaw, Creek and Seminole."
Don't move!
Ooh, that rock still shines in
the dark, boys. Give me that.
Just take the car. Don't take
my ring. My father gave it to me.
Don't want the car.
Just want the jewels.
Y'all didn't do nothing
to earn this anyway.
You like these?
Got us some rich Indians, boys!
Come on!
Come on! Come on!
I'm going all in, boys.
What are you thinking, Ernest?
No. That's crazy, Ernest!
I love money. I love money!
Turn that card over! Boom!
- Come on!
- Yeah! Do it! Hell yeah!
Take a chance!
Fairfax horseshit
right there, boy. Goddamn!
- Queen gets the jewels.
- God! Shit!
"Dawn was always
a sacred time for prayers."
"They call the sun
'Grandfather.'"
The moon, 'Mother.'
Fire, 'Father.'
They call it the 'Flower Moon'
when tiny flowers spread over
the blackjack hills and the prairies.
There are many.
So many, it's as if Wah-kon-tah
looked down upon the earth,
smiled,
"and sprinkled it
with sugar candy."
"Wah-kon-tah means 'God.'"
"You're given your Osage name."
Your name is Sun Hawk Woman.
"It's how you will be called
to the next world.
Your Osage name can never
be taken away from you."
Here. Put this on.
You want dinner?
Yeah.
Don't you want a bite of this?
I got too much sugar.
Can never be too sweet, now,
can you?
It makes me sickly.
You live in this house
just... just with your mother?
I take care for her.
And you live with your uncle?
- Yes. Yes. You know him?
- Mmm.
- Since I can remember.
- Hmm.
He's a nice man.
Why did you come here?
For what?
To live here.
Yes. Um, I... I live here.
Why?
- Uh, for my uncle.
- I work with him. - Mmm.
And your brother is Bryan?
- Byron, that's right.
- Byron.
You scared of him?
My brother? Who?
Your uncle.
Well, no.
No, he's... he's the king
of the Osage Hills.
He's the nicest man
in the world.
- I know if you cross him - what he could do.
- Mmm.
No, I'm... I'm my own
man. I do my own work.
I'm a businessman.
Yeah, thanks.
Here you go.
What's your religion?
- Catholic.
- Mmm.
You don't come to church.
- Oh, yes, um, I've been away.
- Hmm.
How come you don't have
a husband?
I'm a man, and I want to know why a
woman like you doesn't have a husband.
You know, you got...
You got nice color skin.
What... What color
would you say that is?
My color.
Well, I think it's...
I think it's real pretty.
You got nice color skin. You-You
got... You got a nice house.
I think you just pretend
to be so severe.
Bet you... I bet you got a
soft belly on the inside there.
Oh, you just called me
a coyote, didn't you?
Coyote.
Coyote wants money.
- Well, that money's - real nice.
- Mmm.
It's real nice, especially
if you're lazy like me.
I mean, I wanna sleep all day, and I
wanna make a party when it's dark.
What's so funny, hmm?
You like peh-tseh nee?
- Whiskey.
- Mmm.
I don't like whiskey,
I love whiskey.
I have good whiskey,
not bad whiskey.
I think we should try some
and find out.
No, no. No. No, don't close it.
- What?
- Uh, we...
We need to be quiet for a while.
The storm, it's, uh...
Well, it's powerful.
So we need to be quiet
for a while.
- It's good for the crops, - that's for sure.
- Just be still.
Bill Smith.
- Ernest. Ernest Burkhart.
- Good to meet you, Ernest.
I'm Minnie's husband.
It might make you feel a little
better if you eat something.
No, not again. Aw!
He's not that smart...
...but he's handsome.
He looks like a snake.
No, he looks like Coyote.
Those Blue Eyes.
His brother is handsome, too.
I like the brother more.
That red haired rat?
Better than your possum
playing dead...
...and lazing around the house.
He's a possum around you...
...he's like a rabbit to me.
Be quiet...!
...Coyote's watching.
He wants our money.
Of course he wants money...
...but he wants to be settled.
He's not restless.
His Uncle has money...
...it's not money he wants...
...he loves you.
Slow down.
Your hand looks on my skin...
You're gonna marry me, Mollie.
I want you to be my wife.
Will you do that?
Can you stand her kind?
I love this girl. Mollie.
Uncle, I...
I really do think she's a lady.
Well, then you found a wife.
Mollie.
Ernest.
I've known
Mollie and her sisters
since they were little girls running
around, making a lot of trouble.
Mollie's dear departed
father, Nah-kah-e-se-y,
was a dear, dear friend of mine,
a beloved friend of the heart.
He always used to tell the
white men just to call him Jimmy,
but I always called him by his
proper name, Nah-kah-e-se-y.
We had great respect
for each other.
You and me.
Whoo!
Keep going right.
I'm going right.
Minnie.
What do you need for, Minnie?
No, sir.
You well taken care of?
Yes.
You have proper medicines?
'Cause I want you to know you
have the best care if you need.
I don't want you to be afraid.
So many troubles that we've
brought upon you, all of you.
I'm so sorry.
Minnie. My sister.
Wasting illness.
Anna.
Ernest.
Yeah?
Ernest, it might be best
for you to sit outside.
What... Well, why's that?
It's just the way this is going.
If you don't mind.
"The way this is going"? You...
You're saying you want me outside?
Yes, sir, if you would.
All right.
- Bill Smith.
- Mmm.
Yeah.
It shows itself to you
that Bill Smith didn't take the proper
care of Minnie the way he could have.
To have her sick and die, take
her headrights and her land?
That oil, which should go
to her sisters, your wife,
well, he's taking money that,
by rights, should go to Mollie.
The mother, Lizzie.
She's not in good shape.
She won't last.
Most Osage don't live past 50.
With these women dying,
with how Osage suffer
from illness,
you have to make it
the headrights come to you.
You see?
Yeah.
Minnie's gone now,
and after her, that leaves...
Reta... Mmm.
...Anna,
and then, of course,
there's Mollie.
Yeah.
How's Mollie feeling?
She's... She's all right.
Takes care of the little one.
- She's got the, uh... the diabetes too.
- Yeah.
I worry for her sometimes.
She's... She's sick most days, King.
Of course she is. How could she
not be? This diabetes is a trial to bear.
Like it says in the book of Job,
the days of affliction
have taken hold upon her.
Well, Mollie, she's still
strong, King. She's strong.
Yeah, for now.
We hope, forever, but...
What about Anna? You know
Anna carries a gun in her purse?
Hey, what the hell?
I know you get around...
Shit!
What the hell?
Fucking crazy squaw!
Now, I love Anna,
but she's gonna pick a fight
one day with the wrong person.
And then what?
Hey. Stop
it. Put it all on the table.
- Stop it. Manners.
- Nobody's got any manners here.
Did you see the Owl?
When you do...
...it's a sign that we are dying.
Because... of you.
You all marry white men.
Our blood is getting white.
Where's Anna?
I want Anna.
I'm here.
I don't want you.
I want Anna.
Let's get all of them.
This one's whiter than that one.
You'd never know this one's
a half-breed, would you?
They're both a couple of little half-assed
savages, as far as I'm concerned.
Bless their little hearts, now,
they can't help it.
One dark and one light.
And it's like an eclipse.
The Lord put his hand over the
earth and made it shake for nothing.
Oh, goodness.
- Take care, Anna.
- Oh, thank you, sir.
Are you laughing?
Not yet... but...
I brought blankets for Momma.
You're drunk already?
I'm still drunk from last
night, you woke me up.
Don't let Momma see you this way.
Don't fuss on me.
Hello, Anna. You steady?
Oh, I am pickled.
You got any whiskey?
Well, you drank it last night.
Only my man can drink
my whiskey.
I'm not your man.
Well, maybe you don't have
a choice.
Are you making threats?
Hey, hey.
Keep yourself settled down
in here, Anna.
You'll do right.
You're making threats, Anna.
Don't do that.
I'm telling you a secret.
You think I open my legs
for any man?
Well, I get that feeling.
- Hey! Hey!
- Come on, now.
Get her in the other room now.
You are no different,
Ernest. Hear me?
- You are no different.
- Get in the other room!
Older sister, calm down.
Yeah, I'm all right.
You are so pretty.
You know me?
Yes.
What do you know?
Fuck yourself, Byron Burkhart.
- Anna! Anna!
- Hey! Come on, now! Anna!
I will cut you, talking to my man!
I'll kill that woman, then I'll kill you!
- Stand down.
- I'm not your man. I'll do as I please.
Get her out of here!
Give me that. She's got a gun!
Give me that. Come on!
Stay away
from these white women!
Stay away from those
wahk' oh nohn-hohn!
Move!
Get out!
Savage!
Come on, Charlie. Right up here.
This one French soldier, he came
up, he tried to grab that saucer pan.
I saw his leg blown clean off.
A lot of them came back
like this. Shaking.
Hey.
Did you hear they found
Charlie Whitehorn dead?
Aye. Aye. Who did that?
I don't know.
Was it his wife?
Mm-hmm. Most likely.
Now, Anna...
It's time for me
to take her home now.
You're...
...wild.
Anna. Anna, mahn-theen eh-txahn.
Byron's waiting. Come on.
Come on, now.
You're my best blessing.
I'm your favorite?
...stay with me here.
Anna, come on, now.
Stop banging.
Time for me to go, Ernest?
Yeah.
You don't want me here, do you?
You trying to get rid of me,
aren't you, snake? Aw.
You're afraid I'll say too much.
Yeah, I see you're afraid.
You look better.
Why, thank you, Sister.
You're my wealth, you know that?
Don't go out tonight.
You worry
too much, oh-theh-zhoo.
Come on. Let's go.
Okay.
Goodness, let's go find
another drink.
No, I'm taking you home, Anna.
No, you're taking me
to Whizbang.
Byron's taking her home now.
I'm too drunk.
You don't say.
He's taking her home.
Mollie, it's your sister, Anna.
Come on, now.
Come on, now, sweetheart.
Come on.
Is this your sister, Anna Brown?
Pardon me.
Yes...
Two members of our tribe,
Anna Brown
and Charles Whitehorn...
...were both murdered.
These ahn-shdah-heh
are murdering us.
In the case of Anna Brown,
her family here on the west side
have raised funds
of the amount of about
$2,000 to $5,000
for the arrest and conviction
of the murderer.
Mollie Burkhart has hired
a private investigator.
When this money started coming,
we should've known
it came with something else.
'Cause it's
the white man's money.
It's not what we were taught, coming
out of Missouri, Arkansas and Kansas.
What has come to our reservation
that doesn't belong here?
And it's them. They're like
buzzards circling our people.
- Yeah.
They wanna pick us body clean,
leave nothing.
When we left Missouri,
we didn't even leave
our dead babies.
We laid 'em down and we rode
our warriors over 'em
to tell everyone that we'll
never leave this place again.
Or we'll die here,
to the last one.
Yeah. Yeah.
Switch.
Hey, Mollie. Mollie,
words can't express my grief,
but she's with the Lord now.
She's with the Lord.
And they even come here now
to marry our young women.
I employ some of them.
They say they are my friends,
but I don't think they really are.
Some of them
don't even pretend to work.
They walk around, they
act like they own the place.
- Okay, gentlemen. Hold still, please.
- We got it!
I mean, these people are bums,
nee-shdah-heh, common vags.
We can't turn to the county
to help us.
We can't go to the state
of Oklahoma to help us.
Why have we ever even thought
they would?
We were here before them.
This is our homeland we came to.
Yeah. Yeah.
Why we put our children here is
because Mother Earth allowed us here.
Yeah.
No one takes us off this earth
until God calls us all home.
Yeah.
And we've got to realize that,
but we've also got to realize
this evil that's come here.
You have something it wants.
- Yeah.
- It didn't want you when we was coming through genocides,
our coming home.
But now we put the original
25 families together in this room.
Yeah.
And we're here to go with you.
The old saying says is that...
That Osage is dying by the enemy.
Do not let them die alone.
You go join them.
So we can go to heaven
knowing we're still warriors.
We have to change, but before we
do, we need to be like a fire on this earth
and get rid of all that stops
or gets in front of us.
My council, I ask you
for your support.
All of you men. And our women,
these mothers, these ee-nahn here.
All of our elders have
come through this landscape,
and we... only thing we know
is that we have each other.
We have a Lord
that's been good to us.
And this... this other... We
never prayed for the great life.
We just prayed for life.
And that's what
I'm gonna be praying for now,
is that we get that life
for these kids coming.
And, see, our days are over.
We're just barely
living out a sundown,
but their days are starting.
And I want 'em to be Osages, just
like the gift that Grandma gave me,
just like the gift
that Grandma gave you.
Thank you, Chief.
I would like to add a thousand
dollars to that reward money...
...for any information
about these murders.
That means if anyone knows
anything about it, you must come to me.
You all know where I am.
I'm easy to find.
Thank you, Mr. Hale.
Your friendship has always been
greatly appreciated.
I'll do anything, anything, to
help the Osage in their plight,
in their vale of tears.
I move that we send Mr. Barney
McBride to Washington, D.C.
I will second that.
Mr. McBride, Mrs. McBride.
Yes, Chief. I'm here.
Resolution 23. Mr. McBride
will travel to Washington, D.C.
to meet with
the Indian Affairs Commission,
where he will ask for private
investigators and additional police
so that they can look into
this matter of all this death.
Do you accept this?
Yes, I do.
Bill. Reta.
How are you, Ernest?
So you're, uh...
You're here now, huh?
Reta was a comfort to me
when Minnie died.
Hey, listen.
Leave the jewels be on this one, all right?
Oh, I... I do it
so nobody notices.
No, no. Come on, Frank. Just... just
leave it be, just this one time, for me.
It's my wife's sister,
all right? There.
$25 for a hearse rental?
Uh... $1,650 for-for
a mahogany casket?
You charging me Osage prices.
You think I'm thick, huh?
No, everybody pays the same.
Come on, now. McAllister's
entire funeral wasn't more than 300.
This here...
This here's 2,000, Frank.
McAllister's daughter
was just a youngster.
I'll tell you what. I'ma talk
to King Hale about this.
See what he has to say.
Well, if you want her in a
wooden box, I'll put her in one.
I... I don't want no wooden box, all
right? You are charging me Osage prices.
Your wife even said
she wanted an open casket.
But there's no face.
There's no face, Frank.
Why would she want it open, huh?
You trying to steal our money?
Is that what you're trying...
It ain't...
It ain't your money.
It's easy for you to get me
more money and pay my bill.
I work for my money.
Just like the good Lord says,
you sow and reap, Ernest.
When was the last time you've seen
one of them Osages working, huh?
Well, your sister, Anna,
leaves an estate
of approximately $100,000
to be willed to your mother, Lizzie
Q., and you, Mollie, and you, Reta.
You know, I was thinking, that
is a substantial amount of money.
I heard that Tall Chief hired
the Emmett Miller minstrel show
to come in and play
for his birthday party,
and I thought, "Why... Why couldn't we
do something like that with this money?"
Maybe have a party for the town,
and maybe invite another band out.
It does not do
to talk to this man.
Evil surrounds my heart.
Many times, I cry,
and this evil around my heart
comes out of my eyes.
I close my heart
and keep what is good there,
but hate comes.
And they say I ought to kill these
white men who killed my family.
Mrs. Burkhart. Bill Burns.
I solve crimes.
This is my card.
My address is New York,
London, Paris,
Montreal, Chicago, Los Angeles,
Cairo, Berlin, Boston
and wherever else
a law-abiding citizen...
Mr. Barney McBride? Yes.
Telegram for you, sir.
Just arrived.
...hasn't been to Anna's place
to corroborate Byron's story.
Now, I stopped by there, and
I did find her alligator purse,
which could suggest that Byron
is not lying. He brought her home.
Well, my...
My brother's not a liar.
Uh, your youngest sister, Minnie, who
died of the wasting illness two years ago,
she was married
to a "Bill Smith."
Yes.
And that is the same Bill Smith
currently married to your sister, Reta.
Yes.
Same Bill Smith.
Two sisters.
Mr. Smith, he is a busy fellow,
talking around town,
conducting his own investigation
into Anna's death.
- Much obliged, Sheriff.
- Thank you, sir. - Thank y'all again.
Appreciate it.
Were you aware of that?
You were?
Yes.
Now, you went straight
to Mollie's house?
We didn't go straight there.
Where'd you go?
Graveyard out past Florer's.
She wanted to look at her land,
then she wanted to visit her father.
I cannot see my daddy
with my hair flying everywhere.
Did you know I was gonna have
a little baby?
- Oh, my goodness, no.
- Oh, it's true.
I'm gonna name her Minnie too.
Give Minnie my love.
Did you know
that Anna was pregnant?
Anna?
Yes.
Anna was pregnant.
She was pregnant.
Did he say Byron?
No.
Me?
No. No.
Well, you make sure
we steer clear of that.
Mr. Smith says that he has a pretty
good idea who killed your sister.
He says that he will tell all
when he has the true facts.
So what, uh...
What's he found out?
I just don't know that part yet.
Nothing.
I'll go see Blackie.
On that, what we talked about...
About it, yeah.
To see what he may say on that.
That's right.
Ah, yeah. Yeah! Boy,
we gonna be rich tonight, boy!
- Ernest.
- Where's Blackie?
- That's it, huh?
- Yeah.
Osage graves.
That's disgusting work,
right there.
It's dirty. It's real dirty.
You want something
to pay big, Blackie, hmm?
You can't be working
with them trouble boys.
You gotta use your head.
You gotta think, Blackie.
Hale, he's been... He's been
talking about us partnering up.
You know Bill Smith? He's... He's
been going around town talking a lot.
Now, if someone were to knock off
Bill Smith and... and Reta too, right?
If she was gone, all that estate money
would go to my mother-in-law, Lizzie Q.,
and she wills it to my children.
Now, that's a good deal, that.
It's a real good deal.
- For you, it is.
- Mm-mmm.
For all.
Smith and her,
they're gone a lot from home.
All you gotta do is go down there,
and you plant the stand in the house.
- And when they come in...
- ...you get 'em.
They got... Reta's got three or four
diamonds. She got some ear screws.
Bill Smith, he always carries
two or three hundred in his pocket.
You could have that.
You could have that, and... and I know
Hale would pay you a thousand for the job.
That sound like
a good one to you, Blackie?
You know my little
Buick roadster?
You know, the red one
you always got your eye on.
Yeah?
How about I throw in
my Buick roadster?
It's insured more
than it's worth.
Now, I'd get the insurance
money, and you'd get the Buick.
That... that's just a little side
deal between me and you.
Hale doesn't need to know
about that one.
But that's real generous.
Goddamn, you're a greedy Jew, Ernest.
Well, I just love money.
It's true. It's true. I damn near
love it as much as I love my wife.
Ernest?
Yeah.
Come here.
What is it, huh?
Feeling better
than this morning, huh?
A little.
Yeah. You just... You just
need sleep, I tell you, hmm?
Sleep.
That's the first thing now.
I don't sleep anymore.
I know. I know. Just... Just try.
You try to get some rest, all right?
Come on, now.
I don't even know
if you love me anymore.
Mollie, of course I love you.
I need you here.
I'm right here, Mollie.
I am right here.
I love you.
Oh, you gonna try
to wake the kids up now.
You gonna wake the kids up.
Yeah. Yeah.
They're calling it "insulin.
" It's from Toronto and costs dearly.
There ain't more than five
people that can afford it.
It ain't officially for sale yet, but
Bill Hale has seen to it for you.
Did you hear that, sweetheart?
This one. This one.
It's from a cow's pancreas.
- It'll come down to us - once a week.
- Mmm.
Look at that.
Wow. A cow's pancreas.
- Diabetes can be - an awful misery.
- Mmm.
- Have you eaten - in the last hour?
- No.
Lift your blouse, please.
There you go.
Have you had anything to drink?
Goat's milk. Hotcakes.
Well, she's had, uh... taffy
and bacon too. Go on. Tell 'em.
You gotta tell 'em.
If you don't stop eating sweets,
this won't matter.
You will lose your feet, or
worse, if you eat like a white.
Hear that?
It's all right.
Goddamn it.
Hey, Blackie, stop! Blackie!
Oh, shit. Stop!
Goddamn it, Blackie!
Stop running!
- Where are you - gonna go to?
- You gotta catch me first!
Ooh, look at that.
Hey there.
You brought the Buick out, huh?
Get in. Get in.
Byron.
Brother, come here.
- Here?
- Yeah, right there.
Kneel, please, Ernest.
Kneel.
Did you make a deal
with Blackie Thompson
to steal your red roadster
and cash the insurance?
Um...
I, um...
Yes, I did.
Well, Blackie's been arrested
for stealing your car.
What were you supposed to do?
I was... I was supposed to feel
him out on, uh... on Bill and Reta.
So who takes care of Bill Smith
and his blanket now?
I... Hmm?
I don't know, sir.
Remove the book.
I...
I'm sorry.
All right, Brother. Stand up.
Stand up.
Elbows on the table.
I'm a 32nd degree Mason.
I am imbued
with confidence, trust and
responsibility, among other things.
Yes, sir.
You know what that is?
No, sir.
Shit!
Damn.
Now get up! Sit over there.
Are you challenged
to lead your house?
Mm-mmm. No.
She's hired
a private investigator
who noses and brings
unwanted eyes.